scientists explain why left-handed
people as smarter than the rest of us
only about 10% of the world population
is left-handed little Wanda nearly
everything such as spiral notepads and
the likes is designed to have a right
side functioning although we've always
thought less of left-handed people
scientists are finally helping us to see
them differently as they might be
smarter than us for all we know our
dominant hand might be influential than
we actually know a new study published
in frontiers in psychology pals shows
that left-handed people might be smarter
than right-handed folk in this video
we'll be sharing with you some tips on
why left-handed people are smarter than
right-handed people if you're new here
consider subscribing so you won't miss
interesting videos like this first we
need to understand what hand preference
means it's the hand you use most for a
range of activities for instance you may
write with your left hand
but brush your mouth comb your hair wave
to people through or catch things with
your left hand in this case you probably
have a left hand preference
according to IFL science people with a
left hand preference on average have a
more developed right brain hemisphere
the implication of this is that they are
better when it comes to processing and
understanding spatial awareness and
mental representations of objects the
research published in frontiers in
psychology left-handed people
outperformed their right-handed
counterparts in math when those tasks
involved difficult problem solving such
as associative mathematical functions to
a given set of data however when the
task wasn't so demanding for instance
doing simple and magnetic there was no
difference between both left-handed
people and right-handed folks
IFL science found out that a
manifestation of brain function is
therefore related to cognition
when they did a review on handedness and
mathematical ability for left-handed
people they have a bigger right side of
the brain which is responsible for
spatial awareness and mental
representations of objects also they
have a larger corpus callosum the bundle
of nerve cells connecting the two brain
hemispheres which means that
left-handers have enhanced connectivity
between the two hemispheres and hence
superior information processing making
them faster at processing information
than right-handed people some theories
argue that the reason why left-handed
people are faster at processing
information is that we live in a world
designed for right-handed people hence
they are forced to use both hands
increase in connectivity between the two
IFL science tested 2300 students of
different ages in primary and secondary
schools who all asked to perform a
variety of numerical and creative tasks
including writing drawing and
problem-solving the questionnaire asked
several questions about which hand each
individual used for different activities
the research showed that left-handers
outperformed the others as the math
problems got progressively harder when
the tasks involved simple arithmetic the
performances of both left-handed and
right-handed people we're the same
also it was discovered that those who
were extreme right-handed and performed
every activity with their right hand
underperformed in the analysis the
conclusion of this test or analysis show
that when it comes to demanding and
complex mathematics left-handed people
had more advantage and performed better
than the a right-handed counterparts
another study however concludes that
left-handed people slightly
underperformed in developmental measures
but are at more advantage when it comes
to creative processes such as drawing
for instance the brains right side is
associated with creativity in
vision insight and music awareness which
is usually the case with most
left-handed people because the right
side of the brain controls the left side
of the body if you're left-handed maybe
it's high time you stop trying to fit
into the crowd as scientists believe you
might be smarter than most right-handed
people thank you for watching our videos
we'd like to give you another
interesting video for you to enjoy next
but before then our team will be very
happy if you can like this video and
share it with your friends on social
media if you're new here don't forget to
subscribe so you will miss other
interesting videos like this look at
your screen now to see two other videos
we are picked for you to enjoy next we
love you
[Music]
you